Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集里
The Forge of Solus Prime.
卓天越之锤？
Do not ever make me regret which one of you I spared.
别让我后悔今天的选择！
Target the space bridge for Cybertron.
将太空桥指向塞博特恩！
A few swings of that hammer, and bam.
仅仅挥舞了几下锤子 砰的一下！
Our ground bridge is now a space bridge.
环陆桥就变成太空桥了
Megatron has discovered that the Omega lock is on Cybertron.
威震天已经发现“终极之锁”在塞博特恩了
Megatron must be stopped, no matter the cost.
必须阻止威震天 不惜一切代价！
The Autobots have seized  the Omega keys.
汽车人已经抢走了“终极之钥”
We have located the Omega lock.
我们已经找到“终极之锁”了
Autobots, I would suggest that you hand over those keys.
汽车人 我建议你们把钥匙交给我
And if we refuse?
如果我们拒绝呢？
We can all watch them instantly perish together.
我们就可以看着他们一起…痛苦地死去！
Not how I wanted to spend my first trip to Cybertron.
这可不是我所期望的首次塞星之旅…
Starscream.
红蜘蛛！
Jack, it's time to come out and play.
小杰克 出来陪叔叔玩玩？
Go ahead.
有种就杀了我
The Autobots were prepared to sacrifice themselves for my planet.
汽车人愿意为拯救我的星球而牺牲
I'll do the me for theirs.
我也愿意以死相报！
Me too, creepy.
我也是！死变态！
Perhaps we should oblige them.
或许该让他们得偿所愿？
If my decision dooms the future of the Autobot cause on Cybertron,
倘若我的抉择 葬送了汽车人在塞博特恩的未来
so be it.
那也只能坦然接受
But I will never forsake our human allies.
但我决不会弃人类盟友于不顾
Now, if you please,
现在 如果愿意的话
the Omega Keys.
“终极之钥”…
One at a time.
一次换一个
You first, big boy.
你先来 大个子
If I don't get the girl, I'll make you eat this key.
回头这东西要是打不开 我就让你把钥匙咽下去！
You're welcome.
甭客气
Get scrapped.
去你渣的！
If this human was important enough to entrust with the Matrix of Leadership,
如果这个小子重要到连领导模块都值得托付
he's worth two Omega keys.
那么他也值得两块钥匙
No tricks.
别耍花样！
The keys, if you please.
交出钥匙…
Optimus, were you successful?
擎天柱 成功了吗？
Ratchet?
救护车？
It's Joan Darby.
是琼・达比
How are you?
你好吗？
I'm... Eh... Busy, miss Darby.
呃…我很忙 达比夫人
I am expecting urgent news from the Autobots.
我正亟待汽车人的消息
Oh. Is Jack with them?
哦…杰克和他们在一起吗？
No. Why?
不 怎么了？
I haven't seen him all day,
我一整天没见他了
and he isn't returning my calls.
打电话也不接
I will have Jack contact you immediately should I hear from him.
我一有他的消息就让他联系你
Now, if you'll excuse me, I must keep the comm lines clear.
请你原谅 我必须保持通讯链畅通
Ratchet? Hello?
救护车？喂？
Now bear witness as a new era dawns on Cybertron.
现在 见证塞博特恩新时代的开启吧！
Behold! The age of the Decepticons!
看啊 霸天虎的纪元降临了！
By the Allspark.
火种源在上…
- Whoa.
- 哇哦！
Instant home makeover.
瞬间恢复原状了…
Shiny.
焕然一新呐！
You have what you want, Megatron.
你已得偿所愿 威震天
This conflict is between Autobots and Decepticons.
这场战争属于汽车人和霸天虎
Allow me to return the humans to Earth.
让我送人类回地球
Oh, I wouldn't recommend it.
哦…我不建议这样做
They'll be far safer here.
他们在这儿要安全得多
Is the space bridge locked on target?
太空桥已锁定目标了吗？
Per your instructions, Lord Megatron.
正如您指示的 威震天陛下
Excellent.
好极了
Why rule only one world
既然我能统治两个世界…
when I could rule two?
何必只满足一个？
No.
不！
Hey, it's Jack.
嘿 我是杰克
I can't answer 'cause I probably out saving the world right now.
我正忙着拯救世界 暂时无法接听！
Optimus, do you read?
擎天柱 你听到了吗？
An unknown energy spike in Earth's atmosphere is crashing all my systems.
一个出现在大气层的未知能量柱干扰了系统
Please tell me this is related to the activation of the Omega lock.
千万告诉我这和终极之锁被激活有关…
If the Omega lock can restore Cybertron,
既然终极之锁可以让塞博特恩复苏
it'll do the same to Earth, right?
那用在地球上也一样 对吧？
No.
不
It will cyber-form your planet in favor of its new matrix...
它会将你的星球数字化 以便于适应新的模块
destroying all indigenous life in the process.
并随之毁灭所有地球生物
Such raw power!
多么原始的力量啊！
What should I call my new domain?
我该如何命名新的领地？
New Kaon? Or perhaps "Gilded Earth".
新卡隆？或是…“死”球？
No!
不！
Leave our planet alone!
别碰我们的星球！
Optimus, can you read?
擎天柱 你能听到吗？
Ratchet, please open a space bridge.
救护车…请打开太空桥
I guess we should cancel the welcome-home party.
我猜…咱们得取消归乡派对了
Attend to our master!
快去照看我们的主人
He requires medical attention!
他需要医治！
Prime!
擎天柱！
He will pay for dooming Cybertron to remain a lifeless husk!
他放任塞博特恩死去沉沦 徒留躯壳 我要他付出代价！
Hahaha...
哈哈哈哈哈！
They can run,
他们可以逃走
but they can never again run home.
但再也无家可归了！
The children!
孩子们？
What happened?
发生什么事了？
Somebody say something!
你们到是说两句啊！
Optimus destroyed the Omega lock.
擎天柱…毁了终极之锁
What?!
什么？！
You did...
你干了…
What was necessary.
我别无选择
There was no time for another prolonged battle,
当时地球危在旦夕
not with Earth in imminent danger.
没时间从容作战了
So you destroyed the only device in any universe capable of restoring our home?
于是你毁掉了…全宇宙中 唯一能让我们家园复苏的东西？
Optimus, we needed that.
擎天柱…那个我们还有用啊
You weren't there, Doc.
你当时不在场 大夫
And it's not your place to second-guess a battlefield decision.
你没资格去评论战场上的决定
It most certainly is!
我当然有资格！
There had to be another way!
一定有其他办法的！
I-It wasn't that simple, Ratchet.
事情并非那么简单 救护车
Megatron was using the Omega lock to attack the Earth.
威震天当时用终极之锁攻击地球！
Optimus saved our planet.
擎天柱拯救了我们的星球！
What about our planet?!
那我们的星球呢？！
All of our struggles and energon spilled
挥洒了无数的能量
countless sacrifices
牺牲了无数的战友
for nothing?!
到头来却一场空？
Right decision or wrong, what's done is done.
木已成舟 多说无用
And we have another problem here on this world.
我们又有新麻烦了
The Cons just changed the rules when they put Jack, Miko, and Raf into play.
虎子们把杰克 神子和拉夫牵扯进来 他们已经不择手段了
Prime!
擎天柱！
The Pentagon's preparing to go Defcon 1.
五角大楼已进入了一级战备
I need to know what we're dealing with!
我需要知道咱们到底遇上了什么麻烦！
To what do you refer, Agent Fowler?
你指什么 福勒探员？
Maybe you should step outside and see for yourselves.
你应该去户外亲自看看
Ratchet, watch the children.
救护车 看好孩子们
Megatron has managed to accomplish the first phase of his cyber-forming of Earth...
威震天已经完成了数字化地球的第一阶段
the construction of his fortress.
建造他的堡垒
In Jasper, nevada?
在贾斯帕 内华达？
I don't get it.
我不明白
I've already had the town evacuated.
我都把小镇给疏散了
Why here?
他们干嘛要建在这儿？
Because the Decepticons have discovered the location of our base.
因为霸天虎已经发现了我们基地的位置…
Our opportunity to revive Cybertron has been lost
如今 我们痛失了让塞博特恩复苏的机会
due to the treachery of Optimus Prime!
一切皆因擎天柱的背叛！
But from our fortress of New Kaon,
但从这里 从新卡隆城的堡垒开始
we will instead seize control of this world!
我们将征服这个世界！
Decepticons, transform and rise up!
霸天虎 变形 起飞！
I thought he'd never ask!
我等这一天很久了！
Come, my armada!
上吧 我的大军！
Attack! Attack! Attack!
攻击！攻击！再攻击！
Autobots, into the base!
汽车人 撤回基地！
Fowler, what are you doing?
福勒 你在做什么？
My job, two-ton.
尽我的本职
What's happening?
发生什么事了？
What is going on out there?
外面怎么了？
The Decepticons have invaded Jasper.
霸天虎正大举进攻贾斯帕
And Fowler seems to think he can hold them off.
福勒似乎认为他能阻止他们！
Special Agent Fowler to air-defense command.
特工福勒呼叫防空指挥部
I need immediate combat support.
我需要紧急战斗支援
Come on, air-defense command.
快呀 防空指挥部！
I'll be triple-dipped.
一箭三雕
Prime,
擎天柱
reinforcements just arrived.
增援部队到了！
Agent Fowler, your military cannot prevail against the...
福勒探员 你们的军事力量不足以对抗…
You didn't think I was gonna let team Prime have all the fun, did you?
你们不会以为我会让你们独自享乐吧？
Haha. It's Jackie!
哈哈 是老千！
Wheeljack? But how did you...
千斤顶！你是怎么…？
I picked up a strange energy surge.
循着奇怪的能量波动来的
Hope you don't mind the company.
不介意哥们掺一脚吧
No. It's just that after everything... well...
不 只是经过那些事情之后…
We're still on the same team, Doc. Always will be.
咱们仍然是队友 大夫 永远都是
Ratchet, prepare to bridge everyone out of here.
救护车 将所有的人 准备进行转移
We're abandoning the base?
你要放弃基地？
The base is lost.
基地已经沦陷了
Wheeljack and Agent Fowler can only buy us time to escape.
千斤顶和福勒只是在争取时间让我们撤离
Bumblebee, Rafael,
大黄蜂 拉斐尔
you will depart first.
你们先走
You're splitting us up?
我们分头走？
Shouldn't we stick together?
我们不该一起行动吗？
All for one and one for all?
团结一心？
We must disperse to avoid capture
我们只有分散开才能成功突围
until we can regroup and launch a counterattack.
在下次重聚并有能力发动反击之前
Survival is our only priority now.
我们的首要目标是活下去
The day I'm outflown by a bunch of toasters is the day I...
想炸死我 你们还早一百…
We haven't much time.
我们没时间了
Joan!
琼？
You're scrap.
去死吧！
And that's how you wreck a Wrecker.
看谁能来救你 雷霆救援队！
Hahahahahaha.
哈哈哈哈
What about you?
你呢？
I will ensure that the Decepticons cannot follow.
我留下断后 确保没有霸天虎尾随
I... never imagined it would end like this.
我从没想过一切就这样结束了
Neither did I, old friend.
我也一样 老朋友
No...
不…
This is the place, all right?
这里就是他们的基地
This was the place.
这里“曾”是他们的基地
United we stand,
团结一致 我们赢了
divided they fall.
一盘散沙 他们输了